if you have your notes turn over to the
如果你有你的笔记转交给
first section there in your notes called
你的笔记中的第一部分叫做
an introduction to biblical counseling
介绍圣经辅导
and this is where we want to begin an
这就是我们想要开始的地方
introduction of biblical counseling now
现在介绍圣经辅导
in order to help you with this let me
为了帮助你，让我
see if we can share with you a little
看看我们是否可以与您分享一点
bit how I got involved in difficult
我是如何参与困难的
counseling because when sometimes when I
咨询，因为有时当我
share this story it really helps people
分享这个故事真的有助于人们
to understand why I say what I say about
明白为什么我说出我说的话
biblical counseling you've got to
你需要的圣经辅导
understand that when I ever ago went to
明白我以前去过的地方
college I was not focused on Viveca
大学我没有专注于Viveca
counseling or teaching biblical
辅导或教导圣经
counseling at all I didn't even know
咨询我甚至都不知道
what it was that particular time when I
是什么时候我才这么特别
was in college I took a lot of
在大学时我花了很多钱
psychology courses later on went to
心理学课程后来去了
seminary I went to seminary to learn how
神学院我去神学院学习如何
to preach I took every counseling course
传教我参加了每一个辅导课程
they had at the seminary most of it was
他们在神学院的大部分时间都是
psychologically oriented and but I was
心理导向但我是
even concerned about that I just wanted
甚至关心我只是想要的
to learn how to preach that's all I
学习如何传播我的全部
wanted to do and so I started off taking
我想这么做，所以我开始服用了
all these courses in order to go out and
所有这些课程，以走出去，
do a church and learn how to preach from
做一个教会，学习如何讲道
the pulpit now the first church that I
讲坛现在是我的第一个教堂
went to be with staff on I went as an
我 和工作人员一起去了
associate pastor and the senior pastor
副牧师和高级牧师
at that particular time required
在那个特定的时间需要
everybody on staff to go to this other
每个人都在工作人员去另一个
church to get training in biblical
教会接受圣经的训练
counseling now you've got to understand
咨询现在你必须明白
after four years of college and four
经过大学四年的四
years of seminary one of the last things
多年的神学院最后的事情之一
on the planet that I wanted to do was
在 我想要做 的星球上
send in another class all right so I
在另一个班级发送，所以我
really had a bad attitude about this and
对此我真的态度不好
to make matters worse it was a
更糟糕的是它是一个
three-and-a-half hour drive away and it
距离它有三个半小时车程
started at nine o'clock in the morning
开始在早上九点钟
and it went all day until 10 o'clock at
它一整天都持续到10点钟
night and then I had to drive home so
晚上，然后我只好开车回家，所以
when you get tired this weekend I want
当你这周末累了我想要的时候
you to remember that all right
你要记住， 好吧
so it started 9 o'clock the morning so I
所以它从早上9点开始，所以我
had to get up like 4 o'clock get on the
不得不站起来像4点钟就得到
road drive three and a half hours start
公路开车三个半小时
the class at 9:00 in the morning and go
班上午9点去了
until about 2 o'clock in the afternoon
直到下午 2点左右
and
和
all the way over I can still remember
一路走来我还记得
that drive all the way over to take that
一路开车去接受那个
class I was I was actually pastoring in
我上课的时候我实在是在牧养
Ohio at that time and this was a church
那时俄亥俄州，这是一个教堂
in Indiana so I was complaining and
在印第安纳， 所以我抱怨和
sinning all over the freeway all right
在高速公路上犯罪
it was terrible and I finally arrived
太可怕了，我终于到了
and sat down kind of disgruntled open my
坐下来，有点不满地打开了我的心
notebook that they gave me and what are
他们给我的笔记本是什么
these guys going to teach me after I
这些家伙会在我之后教我
just got out of seminary and there's
刚离开神学院，就有了
probably no one on the planet that's
可能在这个星球上没有人
more dangerous than a guy straight out
直接比一个人更危险
of seminary all right guys
神没事的家伙
he believes he's got the whole world you
他相信他是全世界的你
see in his hands but not in God's hands
看到他的手， 但不是在上帝的手中
but in his hands so I started taking the
但在他手中，所以我开始服用了
class and about the second day by the
上课和第二天约
way this class went on for 12 weeks okay
这堂课连续12周好了
and it was Mondays for 12 weeks Mondays
周一是12个星期的星期一
for 12 weeks and the second day of class
12 周和 类的第二天
I had driven over again all the way over
我一路上已经过来了
really unhappy about it in the afternoon
下午真的不高兴
I was asked to sit in on some counseling
我被要求参加一些咨询
and the guy who was the counselor was
那个顾问的家伙是
actually the pastor of the church there
实际上是那里教会的牧师
his name was dr. bill goood he bill
他的名字是博士。比尔goood他的账单
became a later on a very good friend of
后来变成了一个非常好的朋友
mine God has since promoted him to
我的上帝已经把他提升到了
heaven but bill had a counseling
天堂， 但法案有一个咨询
appointment and he had asked me in
约会，他曾问过我
another pastor in the class to sit in on
班上另一位牧师坐在上面
this counseling appointment I said sure
这个咨询预约我说肯定
bill had never seen this couple before
比尔之前从未见过这对夫妇
and so bill shared with us a little bit
法案与我们分享了一点点
about what they had put down on the
他们放下了什么
little introductory sheet that the
那个小小的介绍表
reason why they were coming to
之所以他们来
counseling and so we had prayer and then
咨询，所以我们祈祷，然后
he asked this couple to come into his
他让这对夫妇进入了他的生活
office and I was sitting at one side of
办公室，我坐在一侧
the desk and the other guy that was a
桌子和其他人，这是一个
part of this was sitting at the other
其中一部分是坐在另一边
end of the desk and and this elderly
桌子的尽头和这位老人
couple came in very very well-dressed
情侣穿得很漂亮
the man had a three-piece suit on he had
那个男人穿了三件套西装
long sleeve white shirt with cufflinks
长袖白色衬衫，袖扣
and a nice tie and she had a beautiful
和一条漂亮的领带，她有一个美丽的
dress
连衣裙
and and but you could tell as soon as
和和，但你能尽快告诉
they walked in they did not look anybody
他们走进来他们看起来没有人
in the eye they looked at the floor
他们看着地板
something had had happened and it
事情已经发生了
appeared to be devastating and they sit
似乎是毁灭性的，他们坐着
down sat down and bill had prayer with
坐下来，比尔有祷告
them and he said why have you come to
他们和他说你为什么来
counseling
辅导服务
they kind of hemmed and hawed a little
他们有点皱眉和有点生气
bit about it and eventually he said well
关于它，最终他说得很好
the reason why we came to counseling was
我们来咨询的原因是
and then he stopped he said you've got
然后他停下来说他说你有
to understand that I live a good
明白我活得很好
distance from here I own a company I
距离这里我有一家公司我
have over 300 people that work for me in
有超过300人为 我工作
this company I have been the chairman of
这家公司我一直担任董事长
the board of our church for almost 30
我们教会的董事会将近30岁
years and I was arrested in a public
我被公开逮捕了几年
park for flashing people now I was
在酒店内，我俩的人我是
sitting at the one into the desk and
坐在一进台，
they tell you not to show any reaction
他们告诉你不要表现出任何反应
to what the council he's have to say but
他不得不说的是理事会
I'm sure I look something like what I'm
我确定我看起来像我的样子
trying to picture this old man in a big
试图想象一下这个老人的大事
long coat going into a public park in
穿着长大衣进入公园
the middle of winter and flashing people
中间的冬天和闪烁的人
I'm going Oh what would ever cause a guy
我要去哦，什么会导致一个人
to do that and then they shared a few
做到这一点然后他们分享了一些
stories on how he was arrested for this
关于他是如何被捕的故事
drug his company through the mud it drug
药物他的公司通过泥药它
his church through the mud and drug his
他的教堂通过泥浆和药物他的
family name through the mud
姓氏通过泥巴
they went from the pinnacle of respect
他们从尊重的顶峰走了出来
in their community right down to being
在他们的社区中直到存在
rejected and almost hated by everyone
被大家拒绝，几乎被人讨厌
overnight you could tell us written all
一夜之间你可以告诉我们所有的书面
over her face so I remember sitting
在她的脸上所以我记得坐着
there thinking to myself okay John
在思考自己好的约翰
you've just had four years of psych
你刚刚有四年的心理
classes in college you've had four years
在大学上课你已经有四年了
of seminary you
神学院你
should be able to help these people and
应该能够帮助这些人和
I didn't have a clue what I do I didn't
我不知道我做了什么，我没有
have a clue
有一个线索
I was so desperate I kept thinking now
我非常绝望， 现在一直在想
where would you go in the Bible to
你会去哪里读圣经？
address this issue and the only thing I
解决这个问题，这是我唯一的问题
could think of was David dancing naked
可以想到大卫是赤身裸体的
before God and I wasn't sure how I was
在上帝和我之前我不确定我是怎样的
going to use that it would probably make
要使用它可能会做的
matters worse so I'm not going to use
祸不单行，所以我不打算使用
that text and I was really I'm seriously
那段文字和我真的很认真
I was sitting there with my Bible
我和我的圣经 坐在那里
thumbing to the concordance in the back
翻阅后面的一致性
looking for the word flashing and
寻找闪烁的词
obviously it's not there I didn't think
显然它不在那里我没有想到
it was but just in case I had missed it
这是为了以防万一我错过了它
obviously it wasn't there and I saw bill
显然它不存在，我看到了账单
gewd open his Bible and started dressing
gewd打开他的圣经并开始穿衣
that man's heart and what would cause
那个男人的心脏会导致什么
him to do that kind of thing and at the
他做那种事，并在
same time Minister hope to that woman
同时部长希望那个女人
and I thought oh my goodness he knows
我认为哦，我知道他的善良
what he's talking about I had been
他说的是我曾经说过的
taught a lot of great theology in
教过很多伟大的神学
seminary when I graduated from seminary
神学院毕业时的神学院
I got the Hebrew award and they wanted
我获得了希伯来奖，他们想要
me to go on for my PhD in Hebrew but I
我继续学习希伯来语博士学位但是我
was more interested in going on into
我更感兴趣的是进入
pastoral ministry and so I knew Hebrew I
牧养事工，所以我知道我希伯来语
could parse Hebrew verbs I could parse
可以解析我可以解析的希伯来语动词
Greek verbs and I could translate from
希腊动词和我可以从翻译
the old and new Testament but I couldn't
旧约和新约，但我不能
help people and I realized I couldn't
帮助人们，我意识到我不能
help people I had all these psych
帮助我拥有所有这些心理的人
classes and all I could think of was
课程和我能想到的全部是
maybe this guy's self-esteem is so low
也许这家伙的自尊心很低
needs to be built up I was all wrong
需要建立起来我错了
that's what I've been taught in my psych
这就是我在心理学中所学到的
classes but it's all wrong
上课， 但都错了
and that night three and a half hour
那天晚上三个半小时
trip home I had along this time
这次我回家了
confession time all the way home on the
忏悔时间一路回家
freeway I got home and my wife had just
高速公路我回到家，我的妻子刚刚回家
recently gone to bed kids had kept her
最近上床睡觉的孩子们一直留着她
up late she was already crawled into bed
她已经爬到床上了
kind of half asleep and I came up the
有点半睡半醒，我走了过来
side of the bed knelt down next to her
床边跪在她旁边
bed and because of all my pride and
床，因为我的骄傲和
arrogance not wanting to take this class
傲慢不想上这堂课
I said sweetheart
亲爱的，我说
I'm a lousy husband I'm a lousy father
我是一个糟糕的丈夫，我是一个糟糕的父亲
I'm a lousy pastor will you ever forgive
我是一个糟糕的牧师你会原谅
me I'll never forget she rubbed her eyes
我永远不会忘记她揉了揉眼睛
and she looked at me and she goes I
她看着我，她走了我
don't know what this class is doing but
不知道这堂课在做什么但是
I like it it's really what she said so I
我喜欢它，这就是她说的所以我
was changed at that point from that
从那时起就改变了
point on I started reading everything I
我开始阅读所有内容
could get my hands on which wasn't a
可以得到我的手不是一个
whole lot back then in the era biblical
在圣经的时代回到那时
counseling I tried to drink up
咨询我试着喝酒
everything that these guys were teaching
这些家伙正在教的一切
me from the Word of God which now put
我来自现在的神的话语
handles on my Bible real practical
处理我的圣经真实实用
handles on my Bible to help people with
在处理我的圣经，以帮助人们
serious problems and you know you're
严重的问题，你知道你
among them in your church you know
在你的教会中， 你知道
exactly what I'm talking about and so I
正是我在说什么，所以我
was very dedicated from that particular
非常敬业
point on to make sure that I knew how to
点上，以确保我知道如何
not just dispense the Bible but minister
不只是分发圣经而是传道人
the Bible to people that were hurting
圣经给那些受伤的人
that needed help that needed change
这需要帮助，需要改变
that's what I wanted to do and by God's
这就是我想要做的和上帝的
grace wouldn't you know it here's a guy
恩，你不知道这里是一个男人
who was really oriented towards
谁是真正面向
preaching and even to this day out I'll
讲道，甚至到今天我都会
confess to you I I'd rather preach than
承认你我宁愿讲道而不是
counsel any day because preaching is
任何一天的律师，因为讲道是
easy I mean you can sit in your study
我的意思是你可以坐在你的书房里
all week arrange things any way you want
整个星期都以你想要的方式安排事情
you know put it together and then
你知道把它放在一起然后
present it and rarely are your are you
提出它，你很少是你
ever going to have somebody stand up in
永远都会有人站起来
the middle of a service and say I object
服务的中间，说我反对
to that but in counseling that's going
对此，但在咨询正在进行
to be radically different you're going
你将要完全不同
to start dealing with people's pets ins
开始处理人们的宠物ins
this is the way that they've been for
这就是他们一直以来的方式
years and they're going to get mad at
多年，他们会生气
you they're going to get upset
你他们会生气
so preaching is much more fun it's kind
所以讲道更有趣
of the easy way of ministry when we
当我们这个简单的事工方式时
start working with people in real life
开始与现实生活中的人们一起工作
problems it's different so let's assume
问题是不同的所以我们假设
this may be a huge assumption you're
这可能是一个很大的假设
ready to do that well that's what are we
准备做得那么好，这就是我们
talking about here what are we talking
在这里谈论我们在说什么
about in relationship to biblical
关于与圣经的关系
counseling I want to define it for you
咨询我想为你定义它
and the first thing that I want to do is
我想做的第一件事就是
talk about what it's not before I talk
在我说话之前谈谈它不是什么
about what it is let's clarify this
关于它是什么让我们澄清一下
thing from this true story that I told
我讲过这个真实故事的事情
you about my own life I think it's
关于我自己的生活，我认为这是
pretty evident that biblical counseling
很明显，圣经辅导
really can be and a life changing
真的可以和改变生活
ministry for you as well as for your
为你和你的事工
church it revolutionizes your own life
教会它彻底改变了你自己的生活
first and that's what it did to me see
首先， 这就是它对我所看到的
it had to impact me first I had to see
它必须首先影响我，我必须看到
my own pride I had to see my own
我自己的骄傲我必须看到自己的
arrogance it's something that I think we
傲慢是我认为我们的东西
all struggle with and it's nothing that
一切都在挣扎， 而且没什么
we always get conquered completely but
我们总是被完全征服但是
we continue to struggle with this as
我们继续以此 为奋斗
long as we are sinful human beings but
只要我们是有罪的人类，但是
it it's biblical counseling and learning
它是圣经的辅导和学习
how to use the Bible in very practical
如何在非常实用的情况下使用圣经
ways and the theology of the Bible in
中国圣经的方式和神学
very practical ways that ends up
最终的实用方法
changing us first before it really ends
在真正结束之前先改变我们
up changing other people and I think
我想 ，改变其他人
when you get done with the three weekend
当你完成三个周末
that we are going to present here in the
我们要在这里存在 于
BC da that you're going to say wow I'm
BC da你要说哇我好
really a different person and that's
真的是一个与众不同的人
good because it's the Word of God that's
好， 因为这是上帝的话语
changed you so as we begin here what I
改变了你，因为我们从这里开始，我
want to do is to make sure that we're
我们想做的就是确保我们
talking about the same thing because
谈论同样的事情是因为
there's an awful lot of ministries out
有很多部门出局
there that claim to use Vivica
那里声称使用Vivica
counseling that's what they claim and in
咨询这是他们所声称的内容
our day there are many definitions of
我们今天有很多的定义
what biblical counseling is there
那里有什么圣经辅导
shouldn't be but there are many
不应该但是有很多
different views on what biblical
关于什么是圣经的不同观点
counseling is and of course what is
咨询是，当然是什么
important is what the Bible says it is
重要的是圣经所说的
right that's what the Bible says it is
这就是圣经所说的
that becomes our authority we're going
这成为我们的权威
to assume that you know Jesus Christ is
假设你认识耶稣基督
your Lord and Savior that you have given
你的救主，你给
yourself over to him as his slave we're
自己一遍他为 他的奴隶我们
going to assume that but then beyond
会假设但是然后超越
that beyond that assumption we're going
超出这个假设，我们要走了
to assume that you want to obey the
假设你想服从
scripture especially in this area
特别是在这方面的经文
helping people so what biblical
帮助人们如此符合圣经
counseling is not we're interested in
咨询不是我们感兴趣的
that what it is not and the first thing
它不是什么和第一件事
that it's not it's not an autonomous
这不是一个自治的
ministry that's not what we're
这不是我们的事工
advocating we're not advocating setting
主张我们不提倡设定
up some kind of freelance Center for
某种自由中心
counseling it's not an autonomous
咨询它不是一个自治的
ministry that is somehow isolated from
从某种程度上孤立的事工
the local church or independent of the
当地教会或独立的
local church not at all we don't find
我们没有找到当地教会
that in the New Testament all that's a
在新约中所有这一切都是
secular view we're not talking about
世俗观点我们不是在谈论
setting up independent clinics around
在周围设立独立诊所
Southern California that's not what
南加州那不是什么
we're talking about that's the way
我们正在谈论这就是方式
secular people deal with it that's even
世俗的人甚至处理它
the way a lot of Christian people
方式很多基督教的人
attempt to deal with it they set up a
试图处理它们，他们建立了一个
clinic and depending on the local church
诊所并根据当地的教堂
know it
知道
the church is actually God's ordained
教会实际上是上帝所命定的
instrument that he's chosen to use to
他选择使用的乐器
really affect change in people's life
真的会影响人们生活的变化
for the preaching of the gospel in the
在福音传福音
advancement of his kingdom so we're not
他的王国的进步所以我们不
talking about a freelance center because
谈论自由中心因为
when you get something like that then a
当你得到类似的东西然后a
lot of problems arise for example
例如，出现了很多问题
there's a lack of accountability in
缺乏问责制
those independent centers who are they
那些独立的中心， 他们是谁
accountable to well you may say well
对你说得好，你可能会说得好
they're accountable the state licensure
他们对国家执照负责
may I suggest to you that that actually
我可以向你推荐那个
makes them no longer credible because
使他们不再可信，因为
they have to sign off on that state
他们必须签署该州
licensure that they're going to teach
执照，他们打算 教
the way the state tells them how to
国家告诉他们如何做的方式
teach that's a postmodern way so you if
教这是一种后现代的方式， 所以如果你
a Hindu comes in you've got a instead of
一个印度教徒进来你有一个而不是
converting that Hindu you've got to
转换你必须的那个印度教徒
counsel them on the basis of what a
根据什么来劝告他们
Hindu would accept as good counseling if
如果，印度教会接受良好的咨询
an atheist came in you would need to do
一个无神论者进来你需要做什么
the same thing to violate that would
同样的事情，违反那会
violate postmodern ideas of presenting
违反了后现代的呈现观念
counseling truths the post modernists
为后现代主义者提供真理咨询
would say there are no absolute truths
会说没有绝对的真理
so there's a lack of accountability
所以缺乏问责制
there's doctrinal compromise who's going
有教条妥协的人会去
to oversee the type of counseling it's
监督咨询的类型
being given or sometimes there's
被给予或有时被给予
financial compromise a lot of money is
金融妥协很多钱
given to independent clinics that first
首先给予独立诊所
and foremost should be given to the
最重要的是，应给予
church in order to advance the gospel Oh
教会为了推进福音哦
Lord Jesus Christ
主耶稣基督
so there's compromise you heard about
所以你听说过妥协
the psychologist - several years
心理学家- 好几年了
established a practice in his own
建立了自己的实践
neighborhood and his son grew up went to
邻居和他的儿子长大了去了
college got his degree in psychology
大学获得心理学学位
went on got his master's degree went on
继续他的硕士学位继续
and got his doctorate degree and came
并获得了博士学位并且来了
home one summer and his father said son
一个夏天回家，父亲说儿子
your mother and I have been working
你的母亲和我一直在工作
really hard for years we're going to
多年来我们真的很难过
take off and take a three-month
起飞并服用三个月
vacation we're going to turn the entire
假期我们要转变整个
clinic over to you let you take it all
诊所给你让你全神贯注
for the next three ones son said that'd
对于接下来的三个儿子说'那个
be great dad no problem so dad mom went
爸爸妈妈去了，爸爸没问题
off long trip to Europe came back after
之后，欧洲的长途旅行 回来了
three months saw his son said son how's
三个月看到儿子说儿子怎么样了
it going great practices going great
它的伟大实践很棒
clinics going great
诊所很棒
in fact the son said you know mrs. Jones
事实上，儿子说你认识的是夫人。琼斯
lives about three blocks up the street
住在街上三个街区
from the clinic yeah yeah you've been
来自诊所是的，你去过
seeing her for years oh yeah yeah I know
看了她多年哦是的，是的，我知道
about her will i cured her you did what
关于她， 我会痊愈她，你做了什么
i cured her oh no you didn't she put you
我治好了她哦，不，你没有，她把你
through college and grad school and PhD
通过大学和研究生院和博士
but you get the idea right when you have
但是你有了正确的想法
an independent clinic associated that's
一个与之相关的独立诊所
money driven there's the temptation
钱驱使那里有诱惑
that's intimidation we're not talking
那是恐吓， 我们不是在说话
about counseling independent of the
关于独立的咨询
local church because there's a lack of
当地教会，因为缺乏
accountability there's doctrinal
问责制是有教条的
compromise there's financial compromise
妥协有财务妥协
secondly biblical counseling is not an
其次，圣经辅导不是一个
activity reserved for experts it's not
为专家保留的活动不是
an activity reserved for experts far too
一项专为专家保留的活动
many of given counseling and Gnostic
许多给予咨询和诺斯替教
flavor we're really advocating a model
味道我们真的提倡模特
that any believer willing to be like a
任何信徒都愿意像一个人
Berean that faithfully studies the
Berean忠实地研究了
scripture can follow pastors can and
经文可以跟随牧师可以和
should biblically counseled their flock
应圣经劝告他们的羊群
they should they should be the models
他们应该成为模特
now the Gnostic view remember it is the
现在诺斯替视图记得它是
first century first second century
第一世纪第一世纪
church they had problem with Gnosticism
教会他们与诺斯替主义有问题
the whole Gnostic view is that we're in
整个诺斯替教的观点是我们所处的
the know we have a special field of
知道我们有一个特殊的领域
knowledge not available to the average
普通人无法获得的知识
believer who only has the Bible and the
只有圣经和圣经的信徒
Holy Spirit imagine that only had the
圣灵想象只有这个
Bible and Holy Spirit the two most
圣经和圣灵是最重要的两个
powerful entities in the entire universe
整个宇宙中的强大实体
the Bible and the Holy Spirit but we're
圣经和圣灵但我们
in the know
知情的
and unfortunately there are a lot of
不幸的是有很多
Christians including pastors that have
基督徒包括有牧师
contributed to that kind of thinking now
现在为这种想法做出了贡献
being a biblical counselor it requires
作为圣经的辅导员，它需要
work it requires effort it requires a
工作它需要努力它需要一个
careful study of the Word of God and a
仔细研究上帝的话语和
dependence upon God as Colossians 1:29
像歌罗西书一样依赖上帝1:29
says there's a balance between a
说a之间有平衡
dependence upon God and our
依赖上帝和我们的
responsibility to labor
劳动责任
Paul says I labor striving according to
保罗说我努力奋斗
his power which so mightily works within
他的力量如此强大
me Spurgeon said it like this we must
我司司长说我们必须这样做
work as if it all depended upon us and
好像这一切都取决于我们和
pray as if it all depended upon God
祈祷好像这一切都取决于上帝
right and it does ultimately all depend
对，它最终都取决于
upon God you can't ultimately change
在上帝面前，你无法最终改变
anybody only God can only the truth of
任何人只有上帝才能真相
his word of God can change and this is
他的上帝之道可以改变，这就是
the right balance for anyone who wants
适合任何想要的人的平衡
to do biblical counseling if you're a
如果你是一个圣经咨询
Christian and you're equipped to give
克里斯蒂安，你有能力给予
you're equipped with the Word of God
你配备了神的话语
then you are equipped to give biblical
那么你有能力给圣经
counsel so we're not advocating
律师所以我们不提倡
something that somehow is independent of
以某种方式独立的东西
the local church we're not advocating
我们不提倡 的地方教会
that at all that's not our view we're
这根本不是我们的看法
advocating something that's very much a
提倡非常重要的东西
part of the church it's a central part
教堂的一部分是中心部分
of the very fellowship of a church which
教会 的团契非常 哪
brings me to number three biblical
给我带来三个圣经编号
counseling is not an optional ministry
咨询不是一个可选的事工
it's not an optional ministry it's not
它不是一个可选的事工
something where I think that I've or my
我认为我或我的东西
me and my church can get involved in
我和我的教会都可以参与其中
maybe not I'm not sure it's not an
也许不是我不确定它不是一个
optional ministry because the New
可选的事工， 因为新的
Testament doesn't present it like that
遗嘱没有像那样呈现
at all grab your Bible will you let's go
你抓住你的圣经，你会放手
over to Acts chapter 20 and we're
使徒行传第20章，我们是
interested in verse 20 if you've studied
如果你学习的话，对第20节感兴趣
the book of Acts you know that this is
使徒行传你知道这是
the Apostle
使徒
farewell to the Ephesian Church and I
告别以弗所教会和我
think this is just one model of what he
认为这只是他的一个模型
did with most of the Gentile churches
和大多数的外邦人教会一样
when he said farewell but here we have
当他告别但我们在这里
an example of Paul saying farewell to
保罗告别的一个例子
the Ephesian Church Acts chapter 20
以弗所教会使徒行传第20章
verse 20 he sets himself up in a sample
他在第20节中将自己置于一个样本中
he knows he's not going to come back to
他知道他不会回来
the church and so he says to them listen
教会，所以他对他们说听
I want you to follow my example in the
我想让你效仿我的榜样
ministry do what I've done this is what
事工做我做过的事情就是这样
you need to do and he instructs the
你需要做，他指示
elders to pick up right where he left
长老们在他离开的地方接他
has left off he's modeled it for them
他已经离开了他为他们模仿它
they need to follow this particular
他们需要遵循这一点
model so what does he say he says in
模仿所以他说他说的是什么
verse 20 how I did not shrink from
第20节我怎么没有畏缩
declaring to you anything that was
声明给你任何东西，这是
profitable and teaching you publicly and
有利可图并公开教你
from house to house or some have
挨家挨户或有些人
translated this or in various private
翻译这个或在各种私人
homes now you'll notice that Paul
现在你会注意到保罗
presents his ministry in a two-fold
提出他的事工双重
fashion he there was a public
时尚他有一个公众
proclamation of the Word of God that's
宣告上帝的话语
the form of preaching and there was the
讲道的形式，有
private proclamation of the Word of God
私下宣告 上帝 的话语
that was counseling from house to house
这是挨家挨户的咨询
private public proclamation of the Word
话语的私人明令
of God
上帝
so we've got to get back to an acts 2020
所以我们必须回到 2020年的行动
vision of the ministry most of the time
大部分时间都是对事工的看法
the Ministry of the Word of God is just
神的话语部就是公正的
viewed as a public ministry of the Word
被视为圣经的公共事工
of God not as a private ministry of the
上帝的不作为的私人部
Word of God
上帝的话语
in fact look down at verse 31 he says in
事实上，他低头看着他说的第31节
verse 31 therefore be on alert he says
因此，第31节他要保持警惕
to these elders remembering that night
这些长老记得当晚
and day for a period of three years I
和日，为期三年，我
did not cease to admonish each one with
并没有停止劝告每个人
tears
眼泪
now the word admonish is our Greek term
现在，admonish这个词是我们的希腊词
knew that at that's where we get our
知道，在这其中我们得到我们
word new thetic or sometimes you'll hear
单词新主题或有时你会听到
new feta counseling
新的胎儿辅导
it means it's new that IO means to
这意味着IO意味着它是新的
admonish to warn to counsel can mean any
告诫律师的劝告可能意味着任何
of those things to instruct but in this
那些要指导的事情，但在此
particular case you notice who he
特殊情况你注意到他是谁
instructed not just groups he says he
不仅指示他说他的团体
instructed or he admonished very
指示或他非常劝告
deliberate Greek terminology here each
每个人都有故意的希腊语术语
one you see that each one Paul spent
一个你看到每一个保罗花了
three years in that church at Ephesus
在以弗所的那个教会里待了三年
going from house to house counseling and
挨家挨户咨询和
admonishing everybody in that
在那里劝告每个人
congregation if there ever was a
会众，如果有的话
ministry that was neglected in the
被遗忘的事工
church today it's that kind of a
今天的教会就是这样的
ministry night and day for a period of
卫生部日夜一段
three years and he did it with tears you
三年，他泪流满面
see that in other words this was not
换句话说，这不是
some kind of detached clinical
某种临床分离
Skinnerian kind of counseling white coke
Skinnerian有点辅导白色可乐
approach no no no he was vitally
接近不，不，他是不是很重要
involved in their problems so much that
他们的问题非常多
their problems moved him to tears move
他们的问题他感动得流泪的举动
them to tears is exactly what Paul says
他们流泪是保罗所说的
in Romans 12 rejoice with those who
在罗马书12章中，与那些人一同欢喜
rejoice and mourn with those who mourn
为哀悼的人欢喜哀悼
right there been times where I've
就在我曾经有过的时候
rejoiced with counsel ease and there
在那里轻松安慰律师
have been times where I have cried with
曾经是我哭过的时候
counsel ease that's not some kind of
律师放心，这不是某种
scan Aryan white-coat clinical approach
扫描雅利安白大衣的临床方法
to counseling where people are but
在人们所在的地方进行咨询
animals and they need just behavioral
动物，他们只需要行为
changes that's not it at all that's not
变化，在所有这不是它不
what we're about
我们的意思
we're talking about working with real
我们正在谈论与真实合作
people who have souls who are made in
有生灵的人
the image of their Redeemer and on
他们救赎主的形象
animals
动物
so he went about for three years new
所以他走了三年新
though tattooing I just made up a word
虽然纹身我只是说了一个字
new thought tattooing each one with
新思想纹身每一个
tears that's Paul's personal ministry of
泪流满面是保罗的私人事工
the Word of God so you can see how
上帝的话语，你可以看到如何
important this is let's go over to
重要的，这是我们去到
Romans chapter 15
罗马书第15章
Romans chapter 15 verse 14 he concludes
罗马书15章14节他总结道
the book of Romans with this amazing
这部神奇的罗马书
statement and he says in verse 14 and
声明，他在第14节和第14节说
concerning you my brethren he's speaking
关于你，我的弟兄们，他在说话
to the Roman Church I myself also am
到罗马教会，我自己也是
convinced that you yourselves are full
确信你们自己已经满了
of goodness now he's not talking about
善良现在他不是在谈论
internal goodness but goodness in the
内在的善良，但善良的
way that they treated one another
这样，他们对待彼此
they're full of goodness filled with all
他们充满了善良
knowledge and abled also here we are to
知识和能力也在这里我们是
knew that at one another there's our
知道彼此是我们的
word to warn admonish or counsel they
警告劝告或劝告他们
were able to counsel one another this is
能够律师彼此，这是
what Paul didn't just do himself this is
保罗不只是做自己，这是
not just something that he admonished
不仅仅是他劝告的东西
the elders of the church to do he's
教会的长老做他的
addressing the entire church here he's
他在这里向整个教会讲话
saying I've trained you the leaders in
说我已经训练过你的领导者了
your church have trained you now you
你的教会现在训练你了
need to get busy counseling one another
需要忙着互相辅导
with the Word of God
与上帝的话语
ministering the Word of God to others
将神的话语传给别人
that are hurting in the church now let's
被伤害的 教堂，现在让我们
go over to Colossians 1:28 you see it on
转到歌罗西书1:28你看到了
the screen Colossians 1:28 here Paul
屏幕歌罗西书1:28保罗在这里
again talks about his own personal
再次谈论他自己的个人
ministry and sets up his ministry as the
事工和设立他的事工
model to be followed Paul here says we
要遵循的模型保罗在这里说我们
proclaim him admonishing there's our
宣告他告诫我们是我们的
word knew that at low again admonishing
一句话就知道在低点再次劝告
every man and teaching every
每个人，每个人都在教学
with all wisdom so that we may present
用一切智慧使我们可以在场
every man complete in Christ
每个人都在基督里完成
now what's repeated three times in that
现在什么是重复三次在
verse every man the emphasis is not upon
每个人都强调不重视
groups of people
一群人
the emphasizing individuals teaching
强调个人教学
every man admonishing every man so that
每个人都劝告每个男人
he can present every man complete in
他可以让每个人都完整
Christ Paul said that was my ministry
基督保罗说这是我的事工
and that's exactly the kind of ministry
而这正是那种部
you're supposed to have in the church no
你应该在教堂里没有
doubt Paul was admonishing and teaching
怀疑保罗在劝诫和教导
every man to counter the false teaching
每个人都要反对错误的教学
and to deal with personal struggles and
并处理个人的斗争和
difficulties that they were facing and
他们所面临的困难和
that early church there at Colossae
Colossae那里的早期教堂
faced so let me ask you a question what
所以让我问你一个问题是什么
do you do when a member of your
你做一个成员的时候做什么？
congregation is caught in adultery you
会众被通奸你
say oh you better go see the pastor
说哦，你最好去看牧师
or they're having fits of anger remember
或者他们有愤怒的记忆
we had a man in our church he was a
我们教会里有一个男人， 他是一个男人
carpenter several years ago he never hit
几年前他从未打过木匠
his wife never hit his kids but if you
他的妻子从未打过他的孩子，但如果你
looked at all the interior dirt doors of
看着所有的内部污垢门
his house
他的房子
they all had holes in them hollow
它们都有空洞
corridors he get mad at him and or he
走廊，他恼他，或者他
just get mad and take it out on the door
只是生气，把它拿出门
boom hole in door I remember once in
门口的繁荣洞我记得曾经
counseling I said to him Gary you know
咨询我告诉他加里， 你知道
Jesus said I am the door he got the
耶稣说，我是 他得到了门
point take it out on doors what do you
把它带出门你是什么人
do when somebody has fits of anger or
当某人有愤怒或愤怒的时候
somebody's extremely fearful they're
有人非常害怕他们
controlled by fear they're afraid to go
被恐惧所控制，他们害怕去
to this place so they're afraid to see
到了这个地方所以他们害怕看到
this person or they're afraid to be
这个人或他们害怕
confronted about something or they're
面对某事或他们是
afraid to do something that they know
害怕做他们所知道的事情
that they ought to be doing but they're
他们应该是做什么，但他们
not doing what do you do when you see
你看到的时候没做你做的事
somebody who's in that situation or
在那种情况下或那个人
somebody who's really anxious or
有人真的很焦虑或者
somebody severely depressed in your
有人在你的严重抑郁症
congregation how will you help them it's
会众你将如何帮助他们
critical question will you take your
关键问题你会带走你的
instruction from the world or are you
来自世界的指示还是你
going to take your instruction from the
要接受你的指示
infallible Word of God where are you
无懈可击的上帝之道你在哪里
going to get that instruction how are
要得到那个指令怎么样
you going to help them now there's a
你现在要去帮助他们了
fourth thing when we're talking about
当我们谈论第四件事情
this I want you to understand that
我希望你能理解这一点
biblical counseling is not an entity
圣经辅导不是一个实体
separate from discipleship that's the
与门徒训练是分开的
reason why we call it the biblical
我们称之为圣经的原因
counseling and discipleship Association
辅导和门徒协会
of Southern California it's not separate
南加州它不是分开的
from discipleship discipleship is kind
门徒训练是善良的
of a broad term and we use it broadly in
从广义上讲，我们广泛使用它
fact you can if you do a word study on
事实上，如果你做一个单词研究，你可以
discipleship throughout the New
整个新的门徒训练
Testament you
遗嘱你
find out it's very broad term to speak
发现这是非常广泛的术语
of all kinds of teaching that went on in
继续进行的各种教学
the early church and and the learning
早期的教会和学习
and modeling of certain truths and in
和某些真理的模型
discipleship often when a person comes
当一个人来时，通常会有门徒训练
to Christ they go in and fundamentals of
对基督他们进入和基本面
the faith class or a discipleship class
信仰阶级或门徒阶级
to teach them some of the basics and
教他们一些基础知识和
fundamentals of the faith counseling is
信仰咨询的基本原理是
a subset of discipleship it's very
这是门徒训练的一个子集
targeted discipleship in other words
换句话说，有针对性的门徒训练
counseling really is targeted on
咨询真的是针对性的
specific problems that people are having
人们遇到的具体问题
that they've tried to work on those
他们试图研究那些
problems and by themselves they have not
问题本身并没有
been able to deal with that problem or
能够处理这个问题或
even through their own study the Word of
甚至通过自己研究的话语
God they've not found any resolution a
上帝他们没有找到任何解决方案
problem and so they need someone to come
问题所以他们需要有人来
alongside in a glacial 6/1 sense and
在冰川6/1的感觉和
help them if you study carefully the
如果你仔细研究，请帮助他们
early church this is exactly what
早期教会这正是什么
happened Paul sets himself up as a good
保罗把自己定为好人
illustration of this he he led them to
他带领他们的例证
Christ you can see this in 2nd
基督， 你可以在第二个看到这个
Corinthians 5:17 through 21 and then he
哥林多前书5:17到21然后他
led them to Christ likeness by loving
通过爱引导他们成为基督的样式
them by admonishing them by setting an
他们通过设置一个来劝告他们
example for them to model in terms of
他们用模型表示的例子
righteousness and holiness by teaching
教导中的正义和圣洁
them by reproducing them and disciple in
他们通过复制他们和门徒
necessary all of that is there we're
所有这一切都在我们身边
talking about following that model when
谈论跟随那个模型的时候
people need discipleship in a broad
人们需要广泛的门徒训练
sense then we give them discipleship
感觉然后我们给他们门徒训练
when they need counseling to focus on
当他们需要咨询专注
specific struggles that they're having
他们正在进行的具体斗争
with depression or anxiety or
抑郁或焦虑或
interpersonal relationships or struggles
人际关系或斗争
in their marriage or struggles with
在他们的婚姻中或与之斗争
parenting again the source and our
再次养育源和我们
authority is the infallible Word of God
权威是上帝无误的话语
that's our source that's what we're
这就是我们的源泉
going to go to that's what we're after
要去那就是我们追求的目标
and then we would say this the biblical
然后我们会说这是圣经
counseling is not an activity that is
咨询不是一种活动
insensitive or uncaring you don't say to
你不要说不敏感或漠不关心
people take two verses and call me in
人们拿两节经文给我打电话
the morning that's not the approach now
那天早上不是现在的方法
you can tell from even Paul's example on
你甚至可以从保罗的例子中看出来
how their problems and their struggles
他们的问题和他们的斗争如何
in life moved him to tears in a similar
在生活中让他流下了类似的泪水
way you need to get so involved with
你需要如此参与的方式
those people and they know that you're
那些人，他们知道你是
involved in their life and that you care
参与他们的生活， 你关心
for them we'll talk about that later on
对他们来说， 我们稍后会讨论这个问题
this weekend you care for them so much
这周末你非常关心他们
that their problems and well as well as
他们的问题以及他们的问题
their Joy's move you moves you
他们的快乐动作让你感动
we're preoccupied with everything else
我们全神贯注于其他一切
several years ago I'll never forget one
几年前我永远不会忘记一个
day I was out making a call in people's
那天我在外面打电话给人们
homes late one night and I got home and
一晚深夜回家，我回到了家
walked in the house and usually the
走进房子，通常是
family was in the kitchen at that
那家人在厨房里
particular time when they weren't there
他们不在的时候
and I didn't know where they were and I
我不知道他们在哪里和我
heard some noise coming back from the
听到一些噪音来自回来
den area of the house and so I made my
房子的区域，所以我做了我的
way back in there and as I walked into
回到那里，当我走进去的时候
the den people were sitting around on
书房里的人们坐在上面
couches and they were all in tears and
沙发和他们都哭了
you know when you see a scene like that
你知道当你看到这样的场景
instantly a thousand things go through
瞬间有一千件事情经历过
your mind oh man something devastating
你的头脑哦，男人的东西是毁灭性的
has happened somebody's been in an
发生过某人已经进入了
accident
事故
somebody's died suddenly you could tell
你可以说，有人突然死了
they were just in anguish as I walked in
当我走进去的时候，他们只是在痛苦中
the den a little bit further to ask him
书房进一步问他
what's going on I noticed they were
发生了什么我发现他们是
watching television they were watching
看他们正在看的电视
The Waltons do you remember the Waltons
Waltons你还记得Waltons吗？
and this was an episode maybe you
这可能是你的一集
remember it was an episode where well
记得这是一集好
actually in the previous episode the
实际上在上一集中
whim I have been told it Maryellen had
一时兴起我被告知Maryellen
just recently got married right after
就在最近刚刚结婚
she was married her husband was shipped
她嫁给了她的丈夫
off in the military so she hasn't seen
在军队中， 所以她没有见过
him for a long time and
他很长一段时间了
all of a sudden that postman comes up to
邮差突然出现了
the little farm and the screen door on
小农场和纱门上
the front of that farmhouse and knocks
那农舍的正面和敲门声
on it Mary Ellen you got a letter
玛丽艾伦，你收到了一封信
Mary Ellen comes running down from
玛丽·艾伦· 来自向下运行
upstairs and everybody in the household
楼上和家里的每个人
comes running around and she grabs it
跑来跑去，她抓住了它
from the postman she can tell has a
从她可以告诉的邮递员有一个
military stamp on it and so she's really
军事印章就这样她真的
excited she rips that thing open and
兴奋，她撕开那件事和开放
starts to read it and it's from the
开始阅读它，它来自
Department of Defense telling her that
国防部告诉她
her husband has been killed at Pearl
她的丈夫在珍珠身亡
Harbor
港口
they were sitting there oh I believe
他们坐在那里哦，我相信
after all this time and she waited now
毕竟这一次，她现在等了
we have the capacity to do that with
我们要做的是与 能力
television programs with books that we
有书的电视节目我们
read with theatrical presentations we
阅读戏剧演示文稿我们
see why don't we do that with one
看看为什么我们不这样做
another the issue is not our capacity
另一个问题不是我们的能力
the issue is whether or not we do it we
问题在于我们是否这样做
have that capacity the Apostle Paul that
有使徒保罗的能力
this is what the early church did they
这就是早期教会所做的
were so involved so biblical counseling
如此参与如此圣经的辅导
is not an activity that's insensitive
不是一种不敏感的活动
and caring not at all it's very caring
并且一点都不关心它非常关心
it's focused on the fact that first and
它专注于第一个和第一个事实
foremost we as counselors are humble and
最重要的是， 我们作为辅导员是谦虚的
because we're humble we're going to be
因为我们很谦虚，我们会成为
gentle with where people are at biblical
温柔地与人们在圣经中的地方
counseling is done in a caring way in
咨询是以一种关怀的方式进行的
first Corinthians 415 Paul says he
第一个哥林多前书415保罗说他
worked with people like a caring parent
与像爱心父母一样的人一起工作
it's not throwing Bible verses around
它并没有抛出圣经经文
haphazardly be warm and be fulfilled as
随意地变得温暖并且被充实
James warns us not to do in James
詹姆斯警告我们不要在詹姆斯做
chapter 2 verses 15 through 17 you need
你需要的第2章15到17节
to care about people when you're
在你的时候关心别人
ministering the Word of God to them you
将神的话语传给你们
need to pray for them and you need to
需要为他们祈祷，你需要
counsel them in love and you need to
在恋爱中劝告他们，你需要
allow their problems to move you you say
让他们的问题让你感动，你说
okay
好的
that's what biblical counseling is not
这就是圣经辅导不是
what is it well I'm glad you asked that
什么事情我很高兴你这么问
question number one biblical counseling
问题一是圣经辅导
discerns desires thinking in behavior
辨别欲望在行为中思考
that God wants to change as we saw in
上帝希望改变我们所看到的
Colossians 1:28 it's designed to help
歌罗西书1:28 它旨在帮助
your counsel lead to become complete to
你的律师会变得完整
become mature and to ultimately you
变得成熟，最终成为你
become more like Christ and verse 29
变得更像基督和29节
Paul says he worked to the point of
保罗说他的工作达到了极致
exhaustion he labored and the Greek word
疲惫， 他努力和希腊语
translated striving is where we get our
翻译的努力是我们得到的
English word to agonize he agonized with
英语单词to agonize he agonized with
them and all along Paul says striving
他们和保罗说他们一直在努力
according to his power which so mightily
根据他的力量如此强烈
mightily works within me and the results
在我内部和结果中大力工作
spiritually and the results eternally
精神上和结果永远
are done by God through Paul and through
由上帝通过保罗和通过
us so what is it we're talking about
我们所说的是什么呢？
discerning desires and thinking and
挑剔的欲望和思考
behavior that God wants to change that's
上帝希望改变那种 行为
addressing the whole person and it uses
解决整个人的问题
the Word of God by the Holy Spirit to
圣灵对神的话语
change those desires thinking and
改变那些想法和想法
behavior the Word of God is the chief
行为 上帝 的话语是主要的
diagnostic tool the Word of God is also
诊断工具上帝的话也是
the remedy the change agent used by the
变更代理人使用的补救措施
Holy Spirit in the life of people where
圣灵在人生的哪个地方
they really change internally inside out
他们真的在内心彻底改变了
we're not looking to have people
我们不希望有人
artificially follow the Word of God and
人为地遵循上帝的话语
we're going to learn this a little bit
我们稍后会学到这一点
later that all counseling is pre
后来所有的咨询都是预先的
counseling until a person comes to
辅导，直到一个人来
Christ you cannot counsel an unbeliever
基督， 你不能劝告一个不信的人
you can't do it the only thing the Bible
你不能做圣经唯一的事情
says we can do it that unbeliever has
说我们可以做到不相信的人
evangelize them but you can't counsel
传福音他们，但你不能劝告他们
them now that doesn't mean I won't spend
他们现在并不意味着我不会花钱
some time with an unbeliever but I'm
一段时间与一个不信的人， 但我
always going to bring them back to the
总是要带他们回到
gospel why because
福音为什么呢？
the Word of God for the unbeliever at
对于不信的人来说，上帝的话语
best is a set of suggestions at best and
最好是一组充其量的建议
even if you did get them to obey the
即使你确实让他们服从了
Word of God and what the Word of God
上帝的话语和上帝的话语
says about their particular problem what
说到他们的特殊问题是什么
have you made them into a Pharisee
你让他们成为法利赛人吗？
that's exactly right
这是完全正确的
they're doing it externally they did
他们在外部做它们
they're not doing it from the standpoint
他们从这个角度来看并不是这样做的
of a changed heart all counseling is pre
变化的心脏所有的咨询都是预先的
counseling until a person comes to
咨询，直到有人来
Christ so we have to evangelize if
基督所以我们要传福音，如果
enough will I do good to an unbeliever
我会为一个不信的人做好事
sure I will do good that unbeliever
我相信我会为那些不信的人做好事
needs some help I'll provide them with a
需要一些帮助我会给他们提供一个
little bit of help but I'm always going
帮助 点点 ，但我总是会
to bring it around to the gospel I may
把它带到福音我可能
spend three or four weeks with an
花一到四个星期的时间
unbeliever but if I see that they're not
不信， 但如果我发现他们不是
really interested in change they're not
真的对改变感兴趣他们不是
interested in the gospel at all then I'm
我对福音很感兴趣
casting pearls before swine I'm going to
在猪之前铸造珍珠我要去
give them every opportunity to let them
给他们一切机会让他们
know that I care for them and I care
知道我关心他们而我在乎
about their problem but there comes a
关于他们的问题，但有一个
point at which I believe when you study
你学习时我相信的地方
the life of Christ Jesus moved with the
基督耶稣的生命随着圣灵的移动而移动
movers I can't force the gospel down
搬运工我不能强迫福音下来
their throat I would not be proper for
他们的喉咙，我也不会为正确
me to do so I'm going to go to a person
我要这样做我要去找一个人
who is willing to receive the truth of
谁愿意接受真相
the word of God so biblical counseling
上帝的话语如此圣经的辅导
uses the Word of God by the Holy Spirit
通过圣灵使用上帝的话语
to change those desires and that
改变这些欲望和
thinking and behavior thorough biblical
思想和行为彻底符合圣经
counseling seeks the sanctification of
咨询寻求成圣
the Christian into Christlikeness for
基督徒成为基督化的人
the glory of God that's what we're after
上帝的荣耀就是我们所追求的
we're after Christ's likeness and every
我们追求基督的样式和每一个人
Christian understands that every
克里斯蒂安了解每一个
Christian understands that several years
基督徒明白这几年了
ago Jay Adams went to the International
以前杰伊亚当斯去了国际
Association of psychiatrist and
精神病学家协会
psychologist in Berlin Germany their
心理学家在德国柏林其
annual meeting he was invited to come
他被邀请参加年会
they wanted to hear what is this new
他们想听听这是什么新东西
thing biblical counseling and so he was
事物圣经辅导，所以他是
able to address an audience of about a
能够解决一个关于a的观众
thousand of them and he got up and he
他们几千，他站起身来，他
said to them he said there's one thing
对他们说，他说有一件事
that all counseling has in common we all
所有的咨询都有我们所有人的共同点
are looking for people to change but he
正在寻找改变的人，但他
said the difference between you and me
说你和我 之间的区别
is that you cannot agree what you
是你不能同意你的意思
want people to change into you go from
希望人们改变你的意思
one psychiatrist to another psychiatrist
一位精神科医生给另一位精神科医生
and that and you're going to get a
而且你会得到一个
different opinion on what you want
对你想要什么有 不同的看法
people to come into or change into one
人们进入或变成一个人
of them to behaviorists one of them is a
他们中的一个是行为主义者
family system therapist another one is
家庭系统治疗师另一个是
asking airiness another one is a neo
要求通风另一个是新的
Freudian up whatever it is they can't
弗洛伊德无论如何都不能
agree but there's one thing that all
同意，但有一件事就是全部
Christians understand intuitively when
基督徒何时直观地理解
they when we get done with them we want
他们在我们完成他们想要的时候
them to be more like you understand that
他们更像你理解的那样
we're seeking change into Christlikeness
我们正在寻求改变基督化
that's what we're after that doesn't
这就是我们之后的事情
necessarily mean that all their problems
必然意味着他们所有的问题
are going to go away but they're going
将要离开，但他们会去
to be christ-like in dealing with those
在处理那些问题时要像基督一样
problems so we want to say this that
问题所以我们想这样说
biblical counseling then is new thetic
圣经辅导然后是新的主题
biblical counseling is new thetic it's
圣经辅导是新的理论
that word new thetic is an interesting
那个词新主题是一个有趣的
word because it is actually the
这个词，因为它实际上是
combination of a noun and a verb the
名词和动词的组合
noun is noose which means mind the verb
名词是绞索，意思是动词
is tif Amy and you put and that means to
是艾菲和你放，这意味着
place or to put so you stick them
放置或放置所以你坚持他们
together and you have to place or put
在一起，你必须放置或放置
the idea is sense into the mind that's
这个想法是有意义的
new thought edek this is to place or to
新想法edek这是放置还是放置
put sense into the mind that's what
把感觉放在头脑里就是这样
we're after here are their following
我们在这之后是他们的追随者
references Acts chapter 20 and verse 31
参考使徒行传第20章和第31节
Romans 15 14 first corinthians 4:14
罗马书15 14哥林多前书4:14
Colossians 1:28 clashes 3:16 first
歌罗西书1:28 首先发生冲突3:16
Thessalonians 5:12 514 second
帖撒罗尼迦前书5:12 514秒
Thessalonians 3:15 you can see the way
帖撒罗尼迦前书3:15你可以看到路
it's translated in the King James new
它是在詹姆斯国王新翻译的
American Standard and the New
美国标准与新标准
International Version admonish warn
国际版箴言警告
instruct the idea here is to place or to
指示这里的想法是放置还是放置
put
放
since back into the mind that is
既然又回到了脑海里
biblical sense and the mind becomes the
圣经的意义和思想成为了
key thing and we'll talk about that
关键的事情，我们将谈论这一点
later on because the mind is that part
后来因为想到的是，部分
of man that becomes the control center
成为控制中心的人
sometimes the Bible refers to that mind
有时圣经指的是那种心灵
as the heart I know when we think of
作为心脏，我知道，当我们想到的
heart we think of something radically
我们从根本上想到了一些东西
different but when the Bible or the
不同但当圣经或
Hebrew concept of heart it's not prone
希伯来心的概念不容易发生
primarily emotions the Hebrew concept of
主要是希伯来语的概念
the heart is primarily that of thinking
心灵主要是思考
expectations purposing as a man purposes
期望作为一个人的目的
in his heart
在他的心里
proverbs says so is he it has to do with
谚语说他与此有关
our intentionality it has to do with our
我们的意图与我们有关
desires as a man purposes and desires
渴望作为一个人的目的和欲望
and plans how does he do that he does
并计划他如何做到这一点
that with the heart the Bible says which
用圣经所说的心
at the very core the biblical concept of
在圣经的基本概念
heart is how a man thinks about his life
心是一个人如何思考他的生活
the sense that he brings to his life his
他带来了他生命中的意义了
environment is circumstances and this is
环境就是这种情况
why we call biblical counseling new
为什么我们称新的圣经辅导
thetic pathetic to place or to put sense
理性的可怜或放​​置感
into the mind now I wish we had time
进入大脑现在我希望我们有时间
with those larger group as we have here
和我们这里的那些大集团一样
this evening I would love to be able to
今天晚上我很想能够
sit down with every one of you and get
与 你们每个人坐下来，得到
to know where you're coming from but I
知道你来自哪里，但我
can't do that but there's one thing that
不能这样做，但有一件事
I want you to think about as you go
我希望你在去的时候考虑一​​下
through the sessions tonight tomorrow
明天晚上通过会议
and in the couple of months ahead I want
在 我想要 的几个月前
you to think about is my practice and my
你要考虑的是我的实践和我的
idea of ministry conformed to the New
服事理念符合新约
Testament model
遗嘱模型
and if it is that I'm going to be
如果是我将成为
willing to help people I'm going to be
愿意帮助的人，我将是
willing to give myself to individual
愿意将自己奉献给个人
people that are struggling in my church
在我教会里挣扎的人
in my congregation and to help them with
在我的会众中并帮助他们
the Word of God as I learn how to use
当我学习如何使用时，上帝的话语
the Word of God not just to dispense it
上帝的话语不仅仅是为了免除它
but to minister it in very practical
但要非常实际地服务它
ways to people that are hurting that's
那些伤害那种情况的人的方法
what we're after I started with the
我开始学习之后的情况
story of that man who came into
谁进入了那个男人的故事
counseling and let me end there I saw
咨询，让我结束，我看到了
God radically changed that couple and
上帝从根本上改变了对夫妇和
they actually at the end of that
他们居然在那结束
counseling was able to go back to their
咨询才得以回到自己
home church and go back he was able to
家庭教会，回到他能够
go back to his company he was able to go
回到他的公司，他能够去
back to his family and back into his
回到他的家人，回到他的家
community and actually use this as an
社区，实际上用它作为一个
occasion to humbly admit his wrong and
谦卑地承认自己错了
his sin and to talk about how Jesus
他的罪， 并谈论耶稣如何
Christ through his grace had radically
基督通过他的恩典从根本上说
changed his desires he used that as an
改变了他的欲望，他使用了作为
occasion to point to the glory of the
场合指向的荣耀
Lord Jesus Christ in his transforming
主耶稣基督在他的改变
power and that's what people can do whom
权力，这就是人们可以做谁
you Minister the Word of God to that's
你部部长神的话语，以这
what we hope you will do in the Ministry
我们希望你能在做部
of the word of God so that's our
上帝的话，这就是我们的
beginning we want to start there
一开始我们想要从那里开始
you
您